哈喽大家好
Hello everyone!
今天准备了一筲箕核桃
I have a sieve of unshelled walnuts today.
这核桃是从我们这个树上面打下来的
They are picked from this tree.
由于放久了的话它容易坏
They tend to go bad if stored for too long.
所以现在准备把它加工一下
So I'm going to process them.
四伯爷
Fourth Uncle!?
我拿那个糖来炒哈
I'll stir fry some sugar first.
要得要得要得
Good, good, good!
弄来穿衣子是不是哦
To amber the walnuts, right?
嗯
Yep!
这就可以啊 穿起就好干（吃）呢
That's right. Amber them so they are good to eat.
又香又甜
Savory and sweet.
我来敲你来剥嘛
I'll crack them and you please help unshell.
要得呀
Sure.
我们年轻时候练功夫嘛用手捏还用你敲
We used to hand crack them as a kungfu drill when we were young.
是不是哦
Really?
是嘛
Of course.
你年轻是时候练功夫 你练啥子功夫哦
You practiced kungfu when you were young, but what kind of kungfu?
咋啦 我的功夫高哦
You don't believe it? I'm pretty good!
你要不要我给你演示哈嘛
Do you want me to demonstrate some?
咋子弄嘛
How to do it?
咋子弄
随便咋子弄都可以
Any way you feel good.
顺其自然
Let it be.
该咋子整就咋子整
Do it the way it should.
四伯爷
Fourth Uncle?
嗯
Yep?
你要多吃点这个核桃
You should eat more of these walnuts.
可以啊
Okay.
核桃吃了是增头发的
Walnuts help hair to flourish.
增头发补脑的
Walnuts help hair to flourish as well as help nourish brain.
漆二娃来帮忙剥嘛
Qi-er-wa (second son of Qi's family), please help unshell.
四伯爷我教你我的速度快得很 我给你说
Fourth Uncle, let me show you how to do it in my way. I can do it real fast. Let me tell you.
哎呀 你年轻点肯定要快当点手脚肯定要麻利点撒
Hey, you are younger, and you ought to be faster and more dexterous in your hands and feet.
我们上了年纪手脚笨脚本手的肯定没有你们快撒
We are old now and our hands and feet have become clumsy. We can't compete with you guys.
我年轻的时候你敲核桃 我放在手心里捏一下就烂了
When I'm young, I can put the nut in my hand and crack it with one simple squeeze, while you're knocking it with a tool.
捏一下就烂了啊
You can crash it with a squeeze?
那不是咋子安 我练功夫的时候你试一下嘛
What else? When I practice kungfu next time, I can show you.
这个时候不行了 哎呀
I can't do it now, huh...
这个核桃1斤半
The wallnut is about 1 jin (1 jin equals 500 grams) and a half.
我们配冰糖大概也配个7-8两
Let's mix in some rock sugar, say 7 to 8 liangs (1 liang equals 50 grams).
7-8两应该差不多
7 to 8 liangs would be just right.
不够等一下再加
We can always add more if not enough.
尝一块嘛 四伯爷
Try one, Fourth Uncle.
这个糖这个东西对我来说不感兴趣
This sugar thing isn't interesting to me.
以前小时候还是要偷糖吃
But you must have stolen candy as a kid, right?
以前小时候我干的名堂多得很我给你说
I had a lot of "achievements" as a kid. Let me tell you.
老子写本书的话都有多厚一本
I could write a thick book.
是不是哦
Really?
是啊
Absolutely.
好 差不多了
OK, it's about done.
这个弄来捡起来
This can be used to pick it up.
小时候我没得零食吃都是吃的这个
I didn't have much other snacks other than this, when I was a kid.
小时候 小时候那会儿我非凡
When I was a kid, I was quite special.
现在我们这个核桃仁
Now for these unshelled wallnuts ...
先把它下锅干炒炒香炒脆
Let's stir them in the wok until they become fragrant and crispy.
把这个里面的水份稍微爆一下轻轻的炒
Let's heat some water content out. Stir fry it lightly.
开小火慢慢炒 炒干了之后再放这个糖下去
Keep the flame low and fry it slowly. When it's dry, put the sugar in.
把它炒化
Fry it until melted.
炒成那个带一点点香油色的时候就关火
When it turned to the color of sesame oil, shut off the fire.
这个放下去拌一下
Put in this and scramble.
拌了之后就把它弄起来放到这里面让它凉透分开
After scrambling, take it out and put it here to let it completely cool off, then separate it.
中途我们都可以加点花生碎呀放一点芝麻呀增一下香
We could add some crushed peanuts or sesame seeds to make it even more fragrant.
现在差不多啦
Now it's about done.
下锅了
Put it in.
这刚下去都闻到香了
It's immediately fragrant.
我们在炒这个核桃仁的时候一定要小火
We must keep the fire low when stir frying the walnuts.
就是怕把它炒糊
It's very easy to be burned.
我们要的是把它炒脆炒香
What we want is to stir fry them until crispy and fragrant but no more.
四伯爷尝一下嘛
Fourth Uncle, take a bite.
要得 尝一下嘛
Please, try it.
差不多了
It looks about right.
嗯 好脆哦
Yes, very crispy.
嗯
Good.
炒脆了又香
Crispy and also fragrant.
差不多了噶
This is just right.
嗯 很香
Yes, very flavorful.
好 我们这个核桃仁已经炒脆了
Good. We've made the walnuts crispy.
现在把它起锅
Now take it out.
好啦现在我们这个炒好啦
Good. We've done stir frying them.
先在锅里面加点水
Now put some water in the wok.
水加进去之后把这个糖倒进去
Put in the sugar after water.
把它熬成这个糖浆
Boil it to a syrup.
这下火可以烧大点哦
You can turn the fire higher now.
也要不太大嘛
Not too much though.
这个火候不好掌握
It's hard to adjust the fire just right.
火不好掌握要煤气要大就大要小就小
It's hard. Natural gas stove is better, you can make it high or low easily as you need.
嗯
Yes.
那个才好搞
It'll be better to use that.
掌握不到火的温度
It's hard to adjust the fire.
对
Right.
四伯爷还是个行家哦
Fourth Uncle is an expert.
那还用说啊
You didn't know?
难不成烧的几十年火白烧了啊
My decades of practice isn't a waste.
这点火候都掌握不了啊
How could I not manage this fire.
我们在做这个糖浆的时候啊
When cooking the syrup,
火要稍微大一点点
the fire should be slightly higher.
火要是太小了这个糖容易反沙
If the fire is too low, there could be sugar grains remain in the syrup which makes it taste "sandy".
现在这个糖已经化了
Now the sugar has melted.
开始在冒很多泡泡
It is starting to bubble.
你看我们现在冒很多泡泡
See, it is bubbling a lot.
等到它这个泡泡下去之后开始反香油色
When the bubbling dies down, it will start to turn to the color of seasame oil.
反香油色一点点就可以了
It is enough to have it turn to the seasame oil color just slightly.
我们还准备了一些芝麻等一下一起放下去
We have also prepared some seasame seeds to mix in later.
这个芝麻是已经炒熟了的
The seasame seeds have been stir fried.
好 现在有一点点反香油色了
Now it is turning to the color of seasame oil.
开始冒一点大泡了
It is popping bigger bubbles.
在这个时候就差不多了
It is about ready.
如果你再继续熬的话泡消下去之后下面就是糖色了
If you continue to cook, the bottom will turn to dark brown.
OK 可以了
OK, ready.
我们把这个放下去
Let's put in this.
搞快点
Faster.
快速翻炒
Scramble fast.
这个核桃呢我伯爷他说吃不了太硬的
My older uncle told me he can eat walnuts that is too hard.
所以我就不把糖炒那么老
So I'm not going to cook the sugar too much.
就炒成那个挂霜这个样子就可以了
It's enough to just have a thin shell.
比挂霜稍微老一点点
Maybe a bit thicker and more cooked than just having a thin shell.
耶 好香哦
Yes, so fragrant.
好准备起锅了
Get ready to take out.
现在准备起来
Now get ready.
你看嘛这种大坨的就把它掰散了吧
Break up the big chuncks like this.
嗯 很甜
Yes, very sweet.
你尝哈看 四伯爷
Try it, Fourth Uncle.
哎呀 不用尝都好吃
Hey, I know it is good without having to try.
嗯
Yes.
安逸 又香又甜
Comforting, fragrant and sweet.
现在还正合我的味
This is just right for my taste.
还温温和和的
It is still warm.
还很焦脆
And slightly charred and crispy.
里面脆 糖就不硬
If it is crispy inside, the sugar coat will not be hard.
嗯 就不硬
Yes, it's not hard.
所以这个就看你们的口味来了
So you can fine tune it depending on your taste.
看什么人吃
Depends on who will eat it.
好啦 本期视频就到这里啦
Good, this is the end of this episode.
拜拜
Bye bye.
端过去我们慢慢吃
Let's take it over there to enjoy.